CHAPTER 7.
A Mad Tea Party There was a table set out under a tree
in front of the house, and the March hair and the Hatter were having tea at it:
a door mouse was sitting between them, fast asleep, and the other two were using
it as a cushion, resting their elbows on it, and talking over its head.
“Very uncomfortable for the door Mouse thought Alice; “only, as it’s asleep, I
suppose it doesn’t mind.” The table was a large one, but the three
were all crowded together at one corner of it: “No room! No room!” they cried out
when they saw Alice coming. “There’s plenty of room!” said Alice indignantly,
and she sat down in a large armchair at one end of the table.
“Have some wine,” the March Hare said in an encouraging tone.
Alice looked all round the table, but there was nothing on it but tea.
“I don’t see any wine,” she remarked. “There isn’t any,” said the March hair Then it
wasn’t very civil of you to offer it,” said Alice angrily. “It wasn’t very civil
of you to sit down without being invited,” said the March hair
I didn’t know it was your table,” said Alice; “it’s laid for a great many more
than three.” “Your hair once cutting,” said the Hatter he'd been looking at Alice for some time
with great curiosity, and this was his first speech.
“You should learn not to make personal remarks,” Alice said with some severity;
“it’s very rude.” The Hatter opened his eyes very wide on
hearing this; but all he said was, “Why is a raven like a writing desk
Come, we shall have some fun now!” thought Alice. “I’m glad you've begun asking
riddles.— .—I believe I can guess that,” she added aloud.
“Do you mean you think you can find out the answer to it?” said the March hair
Exactly so,” said Alice. “Then you should say what you mean,” the March hair went on.
“I do,” Alice hastily replied; “at least— —at least I mean what I say— —that’s the
same thing, you know.” “Not the same thing a bit!” said the Hatter. “You might just as
well say added the March hair that I'd like what I get’ is the same thing as ‘I
get what I like’!” “You might just as well say,” added the
Dormouse, who seemed to be talking in his sleep, “that ‘I breathe when I sleep’ is the
same thing as ‘I sleep when I breathe’!” “It is the same thing with you,” said the
Hatter, and here the conversation dropped, and the party sat silent for a minute,
while Alice thought overall she could remember about ravens and writing desks which wasn’t much.
The Hatter was the first to break the silence. “What day of the month is it?” he
said, turning to Alice: he had taken his watch out of his pocket, and was looking
at it uneasily, shaking it every now and then, and holding it to his ear.
Alice considered a little, and then said “The fourth.” “Two days wrong side the Hatter. “I told
you butter wouldn’t suit the works!” he added looking angrily at the March
hair It was the best butter,” the March Hare meekly replied.
“Yes, but some crumbs must have gotten in its well,” the Hatter grumbled: “you
shouldn’t have put it in with the bread knife The March hair took the watch and
looked at it gloomily: then he dipped it into his cup of tea, and looked at it
again: but he could think of nothing better to say than his first remark,
“It was the best butter, you know.” Alice had been looking over his shoulder
with some curiosity.
“What a funny watch!” she remarked.
“It tells the day of the month, and doesn’t tell what a clock it is!” “Why
should it the Hatter. “Does your watch tell you what year it is?” “Of course not,”
Alice replied very readily: “but that’s because it stays the same year for such
a long time altogether Which is just the case with mine said the Hatter.
Alice felt dreadfully puzzled, The Hatter’s remark seemed to have no sort
of meaning in it, and yet it was certainly English. “I don’t quite
understand you,” she said, as politely as she could.
“The door Mouse is asleep again,” said the Hatter, and he poured a little hot tea
upon its nose. The Dormouse shook its head impatiently, and said, without
opening its eyes, “Of course, of course; just what I was going to remark myself.”
“Have you guessed the riddle yet?” the Hatter said, turning to Alice again.
“No, I give it up,” Alice replied: “what’s the answer?”
“I haven’t the slightest idea,” said the Hatter. “Nor I,” said the March hair
Alice side wearily. “I think you might do something better with the time,” she said,
“than wasted and asking riddles that have no answers.” “If you knew Time as well as I
do,” said the Hatter, “you wouldn’t talk about wasting it It’s him
“I don’t know what you mean,” said Alice. “Of course you don’t!” the Hatter said, tossing
his head contemptuously. “I dare say you never even spoke to Time!”
“Perhaps not,” Alice cautiously replied: “but I know I have to beat time when I learn music.”
“Ah! that accounts for it,” said the Hatter.
“He won’t stand beating. Now, if you only keep on good terms with him, he’d do
almost anything you'd like with the clock. For instance, suppose it were nine
o’clock in the morning, just time to begin lessons: you’d only have to whisper
a hint to Time, and round goes the clock in a twinkling half past one, time for dinner!”
(“I only wish it was,” the March hair said to itself in a whisper.) “That would be
grand, certainly,” said Alice thoughtfully: “but then— —I shouldn’t be hungry for it, you know.”
“Not at first, perhaps,” said the Hatter: “but you could keep it to half past one as
long as you liked.” “Is that the way you manage?” Alice asked. The Hatter shook his
head mournfully. “Not I!” he replied. “We quarreled last March— —just before he went
mad, you know—” (pointing with his teaspoon of the March hair it was at the great concert given
by the Queen of Hearts, and I had to sing ‘Twinkle, twinkle, little bat! How I wonder
what you’re at!’ You know the song, perhaps?” “I’ve heard something like it,” said Alice.
“It goes on, you know,” the Hatter continued, “in this way:— ‘Up above the world you fly,
Like a tea tree in the sky. Twinkle, twinkle—’” Here the Dormouse shook itself,
and began singing in its sleep Twinkle, twinkle and went on so long they had to pinch it
to make it stop.
“Well, I’d hardly finished the first verse,” said the Hatter, “when the Queen jumped up
and balled out, ‘He’s murdering the time!
Off with his head!’” “How dreadfully savage!” exclaimed Alice.
“And ever since that,” the Hatter went on in a mournful tone,
“he won’t do a thing I ask!
It’s always six o’clock now.” A bright idea came into Alice’s head.
“Is that the reason so many tea things are put out here?” she asked. “Yes, that’s it,”
said the Hatter with the sigh: “it’s always tea time and we’ve no time
to wash things between whiles.” “Then you keep moving around I suppose?”
said Alice. “Exactly so,” said the Hatter: “as the things get used up.”
“But what happens when you come to the beginning again?”
Alice ventured to ask. “Suppose we change the subject,” the March Hare interrupted,
yawning. “I’m getting tired of this. I vote the young lady tells us a story.”
“I’m afraid I don’t know one,” said Alice, rather alarmed at the proposal.
“Then the Dormouse shall!” they both cried.
“Wake up, Dormouse!” And they pinched it on both sides at once.
The Dormouse slowly opened its eyes. “I wasn’t asleep,” he said in a horse feeble
voice: “I heard every word you fellows were saying.” “Tell us a story!” said the
March hair Yes, please do!” pleaded Alice.
“And be quick about it,” added the Hatter, “or you’ll be asleep again before it’s
done.” “Once upon a time there were three little sisters,” the door Mouse began in a
great hurry; “and their names were Elise Lacey and Tilly and they lived at the
bottom of a well—” “What did they live on?” said Alice, who always took a great interest in
questions of eating and drinking. “They lived on treacle,” said the Dormouse, after
thinking a minute or two. “They couldn’t have done that, you know,” Alice gently
remarked; “they’d have been ill.” “So they were,” said the Dormouse; very ill.”
Alice tried to fancy to herself what such an extraordinary way of living
would be like, but it puzzled her too much, so she went on:
“But why did they live at the bottom of a well?” “Take some more tea,” the March Hare
said to Alice, very earnestly. “I’ve had nothing yet,” Alice replied in an offended
tone, “so I can’t take more.” “You mean you can’t take less said the
Hatter: “it’s very easy to take more than nothing.” “Nobody asked your opinion,” said Alice.
“Who’s making personal remarks now?” the Hatter asked triumphantly. Alice did
not quite know what to say to this: so she helped herself to some tea in bread
and butter and then turned to the Dormouse, and repeated her question.
“Why did they live at the bottom of a well?” The Dormouse again took a minute or two
to think about it, and then said, “It was a trickle well There’s no such
thing!” Alice was beginning very angrily, but the Hatter in the March hair went
and the Dormouse sulkily remarked, “If you can’t be civil, you’d better finish the
story for yourself.” “No, please go on!” Alice said very humbly; “I won’t interrupt again.
I dare say there may be one “One, indeed!” said the Dormouse indignantly.
However, he consented to go on. “And so these three little sisters— —they were
learning to draw, you know—” “What did they draw?” said Alice, quite forgetting her promise.
“Treacle,” said the Dormouse, without considering at all this time. “I want a
clean cup,” interrupted the Hatter: “let’s all move one place on.”
He moved on as he spoke, and the Dormouse followed him: the March Air moved into
the Dormouse’s place, and Alice rather unwillingly took the place of the March
hair The Hatter was the only one who got any advantage from the change: and Alice
was a good deal worse off than before, as the March hair had just upset the Milk
Jug into his plate. Alice did not wish to offend the Dormouse again, so she began
very cautiously: “But I don’t understand.
Where did they draw the treacle from?” “You can draw water out of a well said
the Hatter; “so I should think you could draw a treacle out of a trickle well hey
stupid?” “But they were in the well,” Alice said to the Dormouse, not choosing to
notice the last remark. “Of course they were,” said the Dormouse; “—well in.”
This answer's so confused poor Alice, that she let the Dormouse go on for some
time without interrupting it. “They were learning to draw,” the Dormouse went on,
yawning and rubbing its eyes, for it was getting very sleepy; “and then drew all
manner of things— —everything that begins with an M—” “Why with an M?” said Alice. “Why not?”
said the March here Alice was silent.
The Dormouse had closed its eyes by this time, and was going off into a doze; but,
on being pinched by the Hatter, it woke up again with a little shriek, and went on:
“—that begins with an M, such as mouse traps and the moon, and memory, and muchness—
—you know you say things are “much of a muchness”— ”—did you ever see such a thing
as a drawing of a muchness?” “Really, now you ask me,” said Alice, very much confused,
“I don’t think—” “Then you shouldn’t talk,” said the Hatter.
This piece of rudeness was more than Alice could bear: she got up in great
disgust, and walked off; the Dormouse fell asleep instantly, and
neither of the others took the least notice of her going, though she looked back once or twice,
half hoping that they would call after her: the last time she saw them, they were
trying to put the Dormouse into the teapot.
“At any rate I’ll never go there again!” said Alice as she picked her way through
the wood. “It’s the stupidest tea party I ever was at in all my life!”
Just as she said this, she noticed that one of the trees had a door leading
right into it.
“That’s very curious!” she thought everything’s curious today. I think I may
as well go in at once.” And in she went.
Once more she found herself in the long Haul and close to the little glass table.
“Now, I’ll manage better this time,” she said to herself, and began by taking the
little golden key, and unlocking the door that led into the garden. Then she went
to work nibbling at the mushroom she'd kept a piece of it in her pocket) till
she was about a foot high: then she walked down the little passage:
and then —she found herself at last in the beautiful garden, among the bright
flower beds and the cool fountains